Guide to the Charles Davis Research Files TAM.444
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Charles Davis Research Files
1920-1937
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Davis, Charles
TAM.444
0.5 Linear Feet In 1 box
This collection contains the research files of Charles Davis. The collection mostly contains pamphlets on the development of Pittsburgh and other labor-related writings.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials found in collection; provenance is unknown. The accession number associated with this collection is 1996.021.
Appraisal
In May 2012, a report titled, "A Major Street Plan for Pittsburgh" by the Citizens Committee on City Plan of Pittsburgh from September 1921 was assessed by conservation and deemed unsalvagable due to mold. The report was then deaccessioned.
Arrangement
Arranged by folder alphabetically.
Historical/Biographical Note
While the identity of Charles Davis is unknown, the presence in the collection of an article from the January, 1936 issue of Economic Notes, the periodical of the Communist-associated Labor Research Association, may reflect the left political sympathies of Mr. Davis.
Scope and Contents
Contains pamphlets, writings and reports pertaining to the research interests of Charles Davis. Included are a number of United States Agriculture Department reports, pamphlets and other materials on Pittsburgh's urban planning, and research project material on women workers in Brazil. The materials span from the 1920s to the 1940s.
Writings (document genre); City planning |z Pennsylvania |z Pittsburgh.; Women |x Employment |z Brazil.; Federal government records.; Davis, Charles; Davis, Charles
- "A Business Survey of Pittsburgh's Metropolitan Area", 1928 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- "Cinco Anos de Reorganizacao do Instituto Butantan", Jan 1933 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Citizens Committee on City Plan of Pittsburgh: Parks, Sep 1923 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Citizens Committee on City Plan of Pittsburgh: Pittsburgh Playground, June 1920 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Citizens Committee on City Plan of Pittsburgh: Railroads of the Pittsburgh District, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Citizens Committee on City Plan of Pittsburgh: Transit, Sept (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Citizens Committee on City Plan of Pittsburgh: Waterway, Oct 1923 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Corsman, Greta: "The Working Woman in Brazil", undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
- International Labor Review: Recent Family Budget Enquiries, Feb 1936 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Labor Research Association Economic Notes, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Larkin, Margaret: "Behind the Lives," The Woman Today, May 1937 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Record of Visits to Neighborhood Centers in Typical Districts in Greater Pittsburgh, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Report to the City Council of Pittsburgh on the Inter-District Traffic Circuit, Mar 1926 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Standard of Living and Minimum Wage: Notes and Bibliography, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- United States Department of Agriculture Reports, 1925-1927 (Box 1, Folder 15)